(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
誰にも愛されてない
I'm not loved by anyone
自分が好きじゃないけれども
and I don't even like myself, but...
私メンヘラじゃないもん！
I'm not a menhera!
今日はお誕生日ライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to my birthday live today!
ハイ！
Hai!
盛り上がってください！
Please enjoy the show!
全然やる気が出てこない
I have no motivation at all
もうすでに帰りたい
I already want to go home
お布団が離してくれない
My futon won't let me go
毎日がEveryDay♡
Every day is Every Day♡
あー「あーしろ、こうしろ、あーしろ」って余計なアドバイス
Ah, "do this, do that, do this"—extra advice
やめて欲しい 人生マジ難しすぎじゃん
I want you to stop. Life is way too hard.
オラオラオラオラ
Ora ora ora ora!
たまにはなまけたりしてませんか？
Don't you slack off sometimes?
ふとした時に
At unexpected moments.
完全無欠の5000兆円が欲しい！って感じで生きていっちゃってください！
I want a perfect 5000 trillion yen! Please live like that!
すぐに落ち込んで 泣いちゃうことだって
Getting depressed quickly and crying
赤ちゃんじゃ仕方ないね
Can't be helped if I'm a baby, right?
私メンヘラじゃないもん！
I'm not a menhera!
ぴえんなんて言わないもん！
I don't say "pien"!
あり余ってる感情なんて
Excessive emotions and such,
映えもし映えない もういらない
don't look good, I don't need them anymore
私メンヘラじゃないもん！
I'm not a menhera!
嫌いだって少ないもん！
I have very few things I hate!
移りだしてウザい あー嫌い
Changing and annoying, ah, I hate it
うるさい待てない もう知らない！
Noisy, can't wait, I don't know anymore!
明日の予定だったりさ
Like tomorrow's plans
今月の生活費だとか
or this month's living expenses
気にしすぎてマジ病める
I care too much, it really makes me sick
誰にも愛されてない
I'm not loved by anyone
自分が好きじゃないけれども
and I don't even like myself, but...
私メンヘラじゃないもん！
I'm not a menhera!
ハイ！
Hai!
歌：尾丸ポルカ
原曲：勇魚
Vocals: Omaru Polka
Original: Yuki
MIX/マスタリング：はまひろ
イラスト：あえものえあり
動画：みや。
MIX/Mastering: Hamahiro
Illustration: Aemonoeari
Video: Miya.
時々ガス代払えない
Sometimes I can't pay the gas bill
アイフォンがバキバキ
My iPhone is all smashed up
回しても推しが出てこない
My oshi doesn't come out no matter how many times I roll
毎日がEveryDay♡
Every day is Every Day♡
あー「あーしろ、こうしろ、あーしろ」って余計なアドバイス
Ah, "do this, do that, do this"—extra advice
タコライス？イカライス？
Taco rice? Squid rice?
マジあざっす！あざっす！あざっす！あざっす！
Really, thanks! Thanks! Thanks! Thanks!
メンヘラの正解を肯定して
Affirm the correct answer for a menhera
修正する理性は捨てて
Throw away the reason that corrects you
何とか過ごそう 現代は
Let's try to get by. In this modern era
死んでる暇ない この現世
there's no time to be dead, in this world
すぐに落ち込んで たまに病んじゃって
Getting depressed quickly and sometimes feeling sick
逃げ出すことだって ポンコツじゃ無理もなーの
Running away is understandable for a klutz
あれ？
Huh?
私メンヘラじゃないもん！
I'm not a menhera!
涙なんか見せないもん！
I won't show you any tears!
世知辛いからほら ダラダラと
Because life is hard, see, I'm just
ゆるく毎日を生きてるだけ
living every day lazily
私メンヘラじゃないもん！
I'm not a menhera!
ぴえん…なんて言わないもん！
I won't say... "pien"!
あり余ってる感情なんて
Excessive emotions and such,
映えもし映えない もういらない
don't look good, I don't need them anymore
私メンヘラじゃないもん！
I'm not a menhera!
裏垢だって少ないもん！
I don't have many secret accounts either!
移りだしてウザい あー嫌い
Changing and annoying, ah, I hate it
うるさい待てない もう知らない！
Noisy, can't wait, I don't know anymore!
もう一回お願いします！
One more time, please!
んー！んー！んー！
Ngh! Ngh! Ngh!
そんなんじゃ！
Not like that!
声聞こえねえぞー！
I can't hear your voices!
ああもう無理今も無理心臓止まってるし
Ah, it's impossible, even now, my heart's stopped.
わかんないしもう無理無理無理無理無理無理
I don't know, it's just no, no, no, no, no, no!
やってらんないわ！精神崩壊！
I can't do this! Mental breakdown!
メンヘラじゃないし！全然普通だし！毎日ハッピー！
I'm not a menhera! I'm totally normal! Happy every day!
たまにはなって逃げたって
Even if you run away once in a while,
逃げ出すことだってパンクじゃん
Running away is just bursting, right?
無理もしないで
Don't push yourself too hard.
私メンヘラじゃないもん！
I'm not a menhera!
涙なんか見せないもん！
I won't show you any tears!
世知辛いからほらだらだらと緩く
The world is tough, so look, lazily and loosely,
毎日を生きてるだけ
I'm just living my daily life.
私メンヘラじゃないもん！
I'm not a menhera!
依存なんてしないもん！
I won't be dependent on anything!
有り余ってヘラる感情だって
Even these overflowing, messy emotions,
映えりゃ映えりゃいいもん！いらない！
If they look good on social media, it's fine! I don't need them!
メンヘラじゃないもん！
I'm not a menhera!
裏垢だって少ないもん！
I don't even have many private accounts!
薬なんて大っ嫌い！
I absolutely hate medicine!
うるさい構いもう知らない！
Shut up, don't bother me, I don't care anymore!
通知オフの数奇人だったり
I might be an eccentric with notifications off,
砂糖菓子もいない悩みには
For worries without even a single sweet...
ストロングしか勝たん！
Only Strong Zero wins!
誰にも愛されちゃいない自分が
The me who isn't loved by anyone,
好きじゃないけれど
I don't like her, but...
私メンヘラじゃないもん！
I'm not a menhera!
Thank you baby!
ひゃっほー！
Yahoo!
回せ回せ！
Spin it, spin it!
じゃーん！
Ta-da!
み、右から来るぞ！気をつけろ！
I-It's coming from the right! Watch out!
お前、私より出てんじゃねえぞ！
You, don't stand out more than me!
おいおいおいおい。ほら、あっち行くぞ！
Hey hey hey hey. Look, let's go over there!
え？どこ行った？
Eh? Where did it go?
あれ？さっきまでおったのにな。
Huh? It was right here just now.
あれ、おらん。
Wait, it's gone.
おらんな。
It's not here.
どこ行ったん？
Where did it go?
どこだ！？
Where is it!?
いた！お前、この、この...
There! You... why you...
待て！そいつがルパンだ！
Wait! That guy's Lupin!
おら！あー！
Take that! Ah!
屈折50年、ようやくここまで
After 50 long years, finally chasing him
やつを追いかけてきたが...
all the way here...
一体どこにいるのか、何もわからない。
I have no idea where on earth he is.
一体あいつはどこにいるんだ？
Just where could that guy be?
おっ、なんだ？
Oh, what's that?
あ、気のせいか。
Ah, must be my imagination.
どこに行ったんだ？
Where did he go?
いや、いるじゃねえか！
Wait, he's right there!
どう考えてもどこだよ！おい、姿を現せ！
No matter how you look at it... where!? Hey, show yourself!
ほら、おいでー！おいで、おいで！
Come on, come here! Come here, come here!
そう、いい子、いい子。
That's it, good boy, good boy.
よしよし、おいでー。
There, there, come here.
なんでだ！？なんでなんだ！？
Why!? Why is it like this!?
くそー！えっ、待って、俺落ち...
Damn it! Wait, I'm falling...
次こそは。
Next time for sure.
ハ、ハ、ハッピ...
Ha-ha-happy...
ハッピーバースデー、トゥー、ミー...
Happy birthday to me...
ハッピーバースデー・トゥー・ポルカ...
Happy birthday to Polka...
これはBGMだったかもしれない！
This might have been the BGM!
というわけで、改めましてポルカおるよ！
And so, once again, Polka is here!
ホロライブ5期生の尾丸ポルカです！
I'm Omaru Polka from Hololive's 5th generation!
ついに、ついに、ついに今日誕生日を迎えました！
Finally, finally, finally, I've reached my birthday today!
ハッピーバースデーのコメントありがとう！
Thank you for the Happy Birthday comments!
おお！書いてる、書いてる！サンキュー、ハッピーバースデー！うおー！
Oh! They're writing them, they're writing! Thank you, Happy Birthday! Whoa!
いや、緊張して空回ってんのはいつものこと。
Well, me spinning my wheels because I'm nervous is business as usual.
えー、ま、でも、なんやろな。
Um, well, but, what can I say.
今日もここからお送りしてるんだが...
I'm broadcasting from here today as well, but...
今みたいに、ちょっともう一回歌おうか。
Let's sing a bit more, like just now.
じゃ、みんなと一緒に、もう一回歌おう。歌う、いくよ！
Let's sing together with everyone one more time. Let's sing, here we go!
せーの！ハッピーバースデー・トゥー・ユー！
One, two! Happy birthday to you!
ハッピーバースデー・トゥー・ユー・ミー！
Happy birthday to you, me!
Happy birthday to me...
Happy birthday...
dear... (コメント、コメント... 書いて、書いて、ちょっと)
dear... (Comments, comments... write some, write some, please)
dear ポルカ～！
dear Polka!
Happy birthday to...
ポルカ～！
Polka!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
あ、ありがとうございます！
Oh, thank you very much!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
超幸せなんだが！
I'm so happy right now!
ありがとう。もう、めっちゃ言われて...
Thank you. I'm getting so many wishes...
お、Thank you, thank you! Thank you!
Oh, thank you, thank you! Thank you!
ま、でもね...
Well, but you see...
なんだろう、まあ座員もおるし、コメントもおるんやけど...
How should I put it, I have my troupe and the comments...
うーん...
Hmm...
まあ、ちょっと寂しいよな。曲もこんな盛り上がって照明もあるんやけど...
It's a bit lonely. Even with the hyped song and the lights...
まあでもコメントあるから寂しくないか！
Well, I have the comments, so I'm not lonely!
いいか、こんな感じでじゃあ...
It's fine. So, in that case...
じゃ、こんな感じで今日はやっていきたい...
Let's proceed like this today...
ケーキあります
There is cake
おっ！
Oh!
何これ？
What's this?
What is this?
何、これ...
What is... this?
これ...
This...
マジ？
Really?
え、本当に？
Eh, seriously?
ちょ、誰か、本当ですか？
Wait, someone, is this true?
おお... え、ケーキあるの？
Oh... Wait, there's cake?
ケーキあるらし... え？
Apparently there's cake... Eh?
ないないないない！
No, no, no, no!
おー、チャレンジ...
Oh, a challenge...
ただし、チャレンジに成功しないと食べられません
However, you cannot eat it unless you pass the challenge.
何様だ、おいおい！
Who do you think you are? Hey!
座長がお前、ポルカだぞ！
I'm the troupe leader, Polka!
なんでこんなチャレンジに成功しないと食べられませんとか出てくるんだよ、おかしいだろ！
Why are you telling me I can't eat unless I pass a challenge? That's crazy!
え、どんなチャレンジ？
Eh, what kind of challenge?
え、もう綱渡りしたし...
I already did the tightrope walk...
えーっと、え、綱渡りしたじゃん。
Um, I did the tightrope walk.
玉乗りもしたじゃん、一輪車...
I also did the ball balancing, and the unicycle...
あ、ホロライブ恒例のチャレンジ？何、どんなんだろう。
Ah, a classic Hololive challenge? What is it like?
え、なんか先輩方のやってるチャレンジなのかな。
Is it like the challenges my seniors did?
え、どんなんだろう。
I wonder what it is.
今までどんなチャレンジを乗り越えてきた？
What kind of challenges have I overcome until now?
あーあー...
Ah, ah...
えっ！？
Eh!?
まさか、それはないでしょう。
No way, that can't be it.
ビビりするかな...
Will I be scared...
なんだろう。
What is it?
え？
Eh?
電流？電流はまだ...
Electric current? I haven't done electric current yet...
うわあ！
Whoa!
ガチなやつ...
It's a real one...
火の輪くぐりに挑戦！
Challenge the flaming hoop!
えーっ！？
Whaaaat!?
いや、これよ、だってもう、やばいやつだよ、これ！
No, this is it, I mean, this is dangerous!
これ、いいの？これ...
Is this okay? This...
燃え... あ、なんか火の輪くぐりってなんかこういうなんか...
Burning... Ah, I thought a flaming hoop jump would be like...
可愛い、炎的なエフェクトかと思ったらマジで、熱っ...
A cute flame-like effect, but it's real. Hot...
熱っ。耳、言った気がする、熱っ、熱っ、熱っ。
Hot. I think it touched my ear. Hot, hot, hot.
熱っ。マジで熱っ。
Hot. It's really hot.
え、ど... え、これ、シシローがやるやつじゃん！
Eh, wha... Eh, this is what Shishiro usually does!
なんでポルカやるの？おかしいだろ。
Why is Polka doing it? That's weird.
そういえば、シシローに、なんで座長がやるんだこれ！
Come to think of it, for Shishiro... Why is the troupe leader doing this!
おいおいおい、おかしいぞ、ブンブンブンブンブン！
Hey, hey, hey, something's wrong! Vroom, vroom, vroom, vroom!
えー、じゃあ、なんか頑張るんで...
Well then, I'll do my best so...
「がんばれ」の声ください。
Please give me some "Go for it!" cheers.
がん、がんばれの声ください！
Go, give me some "Go for it!" cheers!
捕食する側から捕食される側になる...
Going from the predator to the prey...
いや、燃える側か。何これ、これまずいって。
No, I'm the one being burned. What is this? This is bad.
明日から配信できなくなるかもワンチャン。
There's a chance I might not be able to stream starting tomorrow.
え、お願いします、誕生日の人です。
Please, I'm the birthday girl.
「頑張って」って言ってください。ありがとうございます！
Please say "Good luck". Thank you very much!
それでは、きっとあるよな。
Well then, I'm sure it's there.
座員君、ドラムロールを！
Troupe members, drumroll please!
あんのかな、わからん、言ってみた、今。
Is there one? I don't know, I just said it.
あ、あるんだ！あるんだ！
Ah, there is! There is!
いつ行くんだ、これ？行くぞ！わーーー！！
When should I go? Here I go! Yaaaaah!!
えーっ！？えっ、今行けた？
Whaaaat!? Eh, did I make it?
え、燃えた？足、燃えた？え？
Eh, did I burn? Did my legs burn? Eh?
燃えてない燃えてない、平気平気。
I'm not burning, I'm fine, I'm fine.
あ、意外ともしかしてこれ熱くないんじゃない？
Ah, maybe this surprisingly isn't that hot?
熱っ！熱っ、熱っ、熱っ。
Hot! Hot, hot, hot.
熱っ。熱っ。
Hot. Hot.
はい、という... 熱っ、熱っ、はい、ということでね、見事成功しました！
Okay, so... Hot, hot, anyway, I successfully completed it!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
ケーキあります
There is cake
お！ケーキ、見てください、このコメントの温度感と...
Oh! Cake, look at this, the atmosphere in the comments and...
この、ケーキありますって言ってくれる優しい座員とコメントの座員。
These kind troupe members in the comments saying there is cake.
見て、この温度感。全然「怪しい怪しい」ってすげー言われてんだけど、おかしいだろ！
Look at this vibe. Everyone is saying "Suspicious, suspicious", how weird!
え、やった、ケーキだ、嬉しい！ありがとう！
Eh, yay, cake! I'm so happy! Thank you!
どこだろう。
I wonder where it is.
どっかからのケーキ
A cake from somewhere.
おお〜〜！　ははは！
Ooooh! Hahaha!
めっちゃあるやん！
There's so much!
え？
Eh?
今日デカいね。
It's huge today.
え！　いいの？
Eh! Is it okay?
え！
Eh!
ケーキじゃん！
It's a cake!
え！
Eh!
ケーキだよ、これ。
It's a cake, this.
初めて見たかもしれん。
I might be seeing it for the first time.
ケー
Ca-
ケーキ、え、え、あ、マジでこれある、
Cake, eh, eh, ah, seriously this is here,
ある、みんな驚くかもしんないけど、ここに
is here, everyone might be surprised, but here,
ガチでケーキが用意されてる。
a real cake is prepared.
え？　ぬ...？
Eh? W...?
ケーキあります
Cake is here
と...　たべ...　食べていいの？
I... can... can I eat it?
今？　え？
Now? Eh?
だって配信中だよ？
But it's during the stream?
あははは！　配信中だよって言いながら
Hahaha! While saying it's during the stream,
フォークすでに手にしてしまった。
I already have a fork in my hand.
いいんだ。
It's okay.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
えー、じゃあ、すみません。
Eh, then, excuse me.
あの、いただきます。
Um, I'll dig in.
え...　え...　あ、あむももも、あむももも。
Eh... eh... ah, munch munch, munch munch.
えー！
Eeee!
えー幸せ！
So happy!
んー、フォークおいしい。
Yeah, the fork is delicious.
んー！　フォークおいしい！
Mm! The fork is delicious!
フォークの味する。
It tastes like a fork.
むげ！
Infinite!
んめー！
Delicious!
甘いもんうま！
Sweet things are great!
おら！
Take that!
最高にうめーら。
It's the best deliciousness.
んー、もっと食いてぇ。
Mm, I want to eat more.
もっと食いてぇ。
I want to eat more.
食いてぇねぇよ。
I don't want to eat anymore.
おい、あぁ食いてぇねぇ。
Hey, ah, I want to eat.
お、もうなくなったんか。
Oh, is it already gone?
おら！
Take that!
このイチゴの部分がうまい。
This strawberry part is delicious.
おら！
Take that!
あむしゃ！
Nom nom!
おらい！
Alright!
これすごくないなんか。
Isn't this amazing somehow?
このまま...
Just like this...
あまままままままままままま。
Munch-munch-munch.
ペロリ！　食べました！
Gobbled it up! I ate it!
あとはポルカが美味しくいただきます。
The rest, Polka will enjoy it deliciously.
このね、あ、待って、
This... ah, wait,
これケーキの中入っちゃったらイチゴちゃんじゃん。
if I get inside the cake, I'm like a little strawberry.
やば！
Crazy!
このね、あのプレートは後で大事にとっておくから。
This, um, plate, I'll save it carefully for later.
へへへ！
Hehehe!
やったー。
Hooray.
超美味しかった。
It was super delicious.
幸せすぎる。
Too happy.
あーもう食べさせられなくなっちゃった。
Ah, now I can't be fed anymore.
フォーク...　フォーク...
Fork... fork...
食べられなくなっちゃった。
I can't eat anymore.
ははは！
Hehehe!
もうちょっと食べたかったな。
I wanted to eat a bit more.
まあいっか。
Well, whatever.
今日は...
Today...
ケーキじゃないよね？
it's not about the cake, right?
It's not about the cake, right?
メインはもちろん...
The main part is, of course...
ライブそう、歌！　シングソング！
the live, yes, the songs! Sing a song!
ということで、何曲か歌わせてもらおうと思います。
So, I'm going to sing a few songs.
ちょっと待っててね。
Please wait a bit.
バイバイ！　ヤッホー！
Bye-bye! Yahoo!
あー...　もう何も考えたくない...
Ah... I don't want to think about anything anymore...
っていうかもう寝よう...
Or rather, let's sleep...
ケーキ
Cake
今日はケーキの夢が見られる...
I can have dreams of cake today...
うんみゃみゃ...
munch munch...
ちょっと食えたのこれ...
did I eat a bit of this...
あー...　このままケーキになるんだろうな...
ah... I guess I'll become a cake just like this...
ケーキになっていくんだみんな人間は...
everyone, humans, will become cakes...
あー...　このまま床になりてぇ...
ah... I want to become the floor just like this...
床になりてぇな...
I want to become the floor...
床になっていくんだ...
I'm becoming the floor...
くちづけキボンヌ
Kuchizuke Kibonnu
作詞：かせきさいだぁ / 作曲：木暮晋也
Lyrics: Kasekicider / Composition: Shinya Kogure
くちづけキボンヌ
Kuchizuke Kibonnu
時はプラニュウ　秋葉原
Time is Planyu Akihabara
黄昏に染まる
Stained by the twilight
寄り添った私たち
We huddled together
影法師ふたつ
Two silhouettes
おれ...
I...
くちづけキボンヌ
Kuchizuke Kibon
あじさい色
Hydrangea color,
ネイビーブルーに
turning to navy blue.
移ろえば
As things shift,
寂しくなる
it makes me lonely.
カラフルな
Colorful
思い出が また焚いて消える
memories are kindled and vanish again.
一寸の 永遠は
A moment's eternity
続かないものね
doesn't last, does it?
今 手と手が
Now, as our hands
触れ合ったのは
brushed against each other,
偶然と
did you possibly think
君は
that it was
まさか 思ってたの？
just a coincidence?
キュンキュンの時間切れの恋を
Repeating this heart-throbbing,
繰り返してばかり
timed-out love over and over,
だけど今日の君は
but you today,
どこか違う
you're different somehow.
永遠の時間切れの恋を
If we break through this eternal,
音速超えて抜けたら
timed-out love past the speed of sound,
君にこう言うの
I'll say this to you:
くちづけキボンヌ
I want a kiss.
永遠の...
Eternal...
草木の露に 学校や友達
In the dew on the grass, at school, with friends,
全てがずっと続くと 誰もが考えていた
everyone thought that everything would last forever.
永遠にオンエアは無く この世の夢は儚く
With no forever on-air, the dreams of this world are fleeting,
印象派の絵具が どこか朧げなように
just like how Impressionist paints are somewhat hazy.
君が帰るべきは 未来なんかじゃなく
Where you should return to isn't the future,
現在(げんざい)かフューチャー そう今 この瞬間
but the present or the future... yes, now, this very moment.
ほら光が 点滅して 二人を包んで
Look, the lights are flashing, enveloping the two of us.
秋葉の夕まぐれに
In the twilight of Akiba,
二人は 二人は 二人は
the two of us, the two of us, the two of us.
キュンキュンの時間切れの恋を
Repeating this heart-throbbing,
繰り返してばかり
timed-out love over and over,
だけど今日の君は
but you today,
どこか違う
you're different somehow.
永遠の時間切れの恋を
If we break through this eternal,
音速超えて抜けたら
timed-out love past the speed of sound,
君にこう言うの
I'll say this to you:
くちづけキボンヌ
I want a kiss.
永遠の...
Eternal...
尽きたよって
Even if I don't say
言わなくても
it's over,
伝わっていると
did you possibly think
まさか
that it was
思ってたの？
already understood?
キュンキュンの時間切れの恋を
Repeating this heart-throbbing,
繰り返してばかり
timed-out love over and over,
だけど今日の君は
but you today,
どこか違う
you're different somehow.
永遠の時間切れの恋を
If we break through this eternal,
音速超えて抜けたら
timed-out love past the speed of sound,
君にこう言うの
I'll say this to you:
くちづけキボンヌ
I want a kiss.
永遠の...
Eternal...
あした地球がこなごなになっても
Even if the Earth were to be smashed into pieces tomorrow
作詞：浅野いにお / 作曲：釣俊輔
Lyrics: Inio Asano / Composition: Shunsuke Tsuri
不遇な部屋に住み それとなく疲れてて
Living in an unfortunate room, being somewhat tired,
とはいえ お仕事は とても順順なの
and yet, work is going very smoothly.
とりあえず
For now,
振り返ったら
if I look back...
路地裏から猫がみてた
A cat was watching from a back alley
この声聞こえていますか
Can you hear this voice?
私ってちょっと強くなったと思うよ
I think I've become a little stronger
だけどきっと
But surely
あした地球がこなごなになって
If the Earth shatters tomorrow
宇宙の塵になって消えたら
And vanishes as stardust in space
プリズムみたいなお洒落して
I'll dress up like a prism
咲いて咲いて寝込んでやる
Blooming, blooming, then I'll collapse
強がりばかりくたくたになって
Getting exhausted from all my bluffing
泣いちゃうこともあるからさ
Because sometimes I'll end up crying
ギュッと抱き寄せて
Hold me tight
それだけなの それだけなの
That's all... that's all
お願い
Please
夜しじまに溶けていく歌電波を
A song melting into the night's silence, sending out waves
手探りで書き留めたあのあの日々は
Those days when I fumbled to write them down
まだ夜も明けていないのに
Even though the night hasn't ended yet
終わりばかりを気にしてた
I was only worried about the end
この声聞こえていますか
Can you hear this voice?
私って結構頑張ってると思うよ
I think I'm working pretty hard
だけどきっと
But surely
あした地球がこなごなになって
If the Earth shatters tomorrow
宇宙の塵になって消えたら
And vanishes as stardust in space
オーロラみたいなメイクして
I'll put on makeup like an aurora
咲いて咲いて死んでやる
Blooming, blooming, then I'll die
怖くはないよくたくたになって
I'm not afraid, even if I get exhausted
怠けることもあるけれどさ
I might slack off sometimes too
ギュッと抱き寄せて
Hold me tight
無理してるの 無理してるよ
I'm pushing myself, I'm pushing myself
ごめんね
I'm sorry
瞬いている粒たちが
The twinkling particles
サラサラ流れる
Flowing smoothly
星の行方は
The whereabouts of the stars
いつかここへおいで
Come here someday
君がいるなら
If you are there
たとえ世界が終わる日も
Even on the day the world ends
夢中夢中抱きしめて
Hold me tight, lost in a dream
最高のステージ見せてやる
I'll show you the best stage ever
360度空に浮かんで
Floating 360 degrees in the sky
太陽だってもう捕まえに行こう
Let's go and catch even the sun
きっと約束だよ
It's a promise, for sure
約束だよ
It's a promise
お願い
Please
今日は結構しんみりした感じになっちゃったっていうか
Today got a bit sentimental, I guess...
あんまりポルカが歌ってこなかったバラードを歌っています
I'm singing a ballad, which isn't something Polka usually sings.
でんぱ組.incさんで「あした地球がこなごなになっても」
That was "Even if the Earth Shatters Tomorrow" by Denpagumi.inc.
あした地球がこなごなになってもでした...
Tomorrow, even if the earth is shattered...
あー　はあ　拍手ありがとうございます。
Ah, whew... thank you for the applause.
えっと、そうですね。まあ、残りの二曲も...
Um, let's see. Well, for the remaining two songs...
あっ、言っちゃった！
Ah, I said it!
まあ残りの二曲歌うんだけど、
Well, I'm going to sing the remaining two songs,
二曲とも、すごいぶち上がる感じじゃないけど、
and while they might not be super high-energy,
まあ今日ならではっていうかな、
they are songs unique to today, I suppose,
歌うので、お願いいたします。
so please listen to them.
そちらも、よろしくお願いします。
I hope you enjoy those as well.
聴いてください。花に亡霊。
Please listen. "Ghost in a Flower."
花に亡霊
Ghost in a Flower
作詞・作曲 / n-buna
Lyrics & Composition: n-buna
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you forgotten it already?
夏の木陰に座ったまま
Still sitting in the summer shade,
アイスを口に放り込んで
Popping an ice cream into my mouth,
風を待っていた
Waiting for the breeze.
待ってたかな
Was I waiting?
世の中の全部嘘だらけ
The whole world is full of lies.
本当の価値を二人で探しに行こうと笑ったこと
How we laughed about searching for true value together.
忘れないように
So I don't forget,
色褪せないように
so it doesn't fade,
形に残るものがすべてじゃないように
so that things with physical form aren't everything.
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words,
夏が来るって教えて
tell me that summer is coming.
僕は描いてる 目に映ったのは夏の亡霊だ
I'm drawing. What was in my eyes was a summer ghost.
風にスカートが揺れて
A skirt sways in the wind,
思い出なんて忘れて
forget all the memories,
浅い呼吸をする
taking shallow breaths.
汗を拭って夏めく
Wiping away sweat, feeling the summer.
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you forgotten it already?
夏の木陰に座った頃
Back when we sat in the summer shade,
遠くの丘から顔を出した雲があったじゃないか
wasn't there a cloud peeking out from the distant hill?
君はそれを掴もうとして
You tried to catch it,
馬鹿みたいに空を切った手で
with hands that cut through the air like a fool.
僕は紙に雲一つ書いて 笑って握って見せて
I drew a cloud on paper, laughed, and showed it to you.
忘れないように
So I don't forget,
色褪せないように
so it doesn't fade,
歴史に残るものがすべてじゃないから
because things left in history aren't everything.
今だけ顔をなくして
Let's lose our faces just for now,
言葉も全部忘れて
and forget all words too.
君は笑ってる 夏を待ってる 僕ら亡霊だ
You're laughing, waiting for summer. We're ghosts.
心をもっと教えて
Tell me more about your heart,
夏の匂いを教えて
tell me about the scent of summer.
浅い呼吸をする
Taking shallow breaths.
忘れないように
So I don't forget,
色褪せないように
so it doesn't fade,
心に響くものがすべてじゃないから
because things that resonate aren't everything.
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words,
さよならだって教えて
tell me even "goodbye."
今も見るんだよ 夏に咲いてる 花に亡霊を
I still see it today. The ghost in the summer flower.
言葉じゃなくて時間を
Not words, but time.
時間じゃなくて心を
Not time, but heart.
浅い呼吸をする
Taking shallow breaths.
汗を拭って夏めく
Wiping away sweat, feeling the summer.
夏の匂いをする
Smelling of summer.
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you forgotten it already?
夏の木陰に座ったまま
Still sitting in the summer shade,
アイスを口に放り込んで
popping an ice cream into my mouth,
風を待って...
waiting for the breeze...
花に亡霊
Ghost in a Flower
待っていた...
I was waiting...
次の曲です。
The next song.
新しい曲を覚えると
When I learn a new song,
少し
I get a little bit
シルシ
作詞：LiSA / 作曲：カヨコ
Shirushi
Lyrics: LiSA / Composition: Kayoko
近づいてしまうのが
closer, and that
悔しい。
is frustrating.
照らした
Illuminated
賑やかな笑い声と
With the bustling laughter
路地裏の足跡
And footprints in the alleyway
伝えたい想いはどれだけ届いたんだろう
How much of the feelings I want to convey reached you?
いつも振り向いて確かめる
I always turn around and check
いつだって迷わず君はきっと
No matter when, without hesitation, you surely...
どんな僕も追いかけてくれるから
Because you'll chase after any version of me
じっと見つめた君の瞳に
In your eyes that I gazed into intensely
映った僕が生きるシルシ
Is the sign that the "me" reflected there is alive
何度も途切れそうな鼓動を
The heartbeat that seemed like it would cut out many times
強く強く鳴らした
I made it beat strongly, so strongly
今日を越えてみたいんだ
I want to try and make it past today
手にした幸せを失うことを恐れて
Fearing that I'll lose the happiness I've gained
立ち止まっているよりも
Rather than just standing still
一つ一つ大きな
One by one, big...
できるだけ多くの笑顔咲かせようと
Trying to make as many smiles bloom as possible
思い出すくらいの通り過ぎた日々が
So that the days passed that I remember
いつも輝いて見えるように
Always look like they're shining
ぎゅっと握った君の温もりで
With your warmth that I held onto tightly
感じた僕ら繋いだ証
I felt the proof of our connection
君と今同じ空の下
Under the same sky as you now
あの日描いた未来を歩いている
I'm walking the future we envisioned that day
いくつ願い叶えても
No matter how many wishes come true
君と過ごした新しい明日を
A new tomorrow spent with you
すぐに次々に僕はきっとまた願ってしまうから
I'm sure I'll just keep wishing for them one after another
響け
Echo
いつか僕らを攫ってくから
Because it will take us away someday
瞬きした隙に君の見せるすべてを
Everything you show me in the blink of an eye
見落とさないように
So that I don't miss any of it
じっと見つめた君の瞳に
In your eyes that I gazed into intensely
映った僕が生きるシルシ
Is the sign that the "me" reflected there is alive
何度も途切れそうな鼓動を
The heartbeat that seemed like it would cut out many times
強く強く鳴らした
I made it beat strongly, so strongly
今日を越えて行けなくても 君と生きたい
Even if I can't make it past today, I want to live with you
空は 忘れない...
The sky will never forget...
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
あー。
Ah...
やっほー！ほー！ほー！
Yoo-hoo! Hoo! Hoo!
跳ね返るわけもないか。
I guess there won't be an echo.
うー...ああー！ああー！
Ugh... Ahhh! Ahhh!
空気が気持ちいいなあ。
The air feels so good.
あ、あそこに綿綿先輩いるじゃん。おーい！綿綿先輩！
Oh, there's Watame-senpai over there. Hey! Watame-senpai!
あ、綿綿先輩？え？綿綿先輩？
Ah, Watame-senpai? Huh? Watame-senpai?
え、誰、誰、誰、これ大丈夫か？
Wait, who, who, who is this? Is this okay?
まあ、どうにかなるだろ。
Well, I'm sure it'll be fine.
明日からもいい日が続きそうだ。
Looks like good days will continue from tomorrow too.
あ、UFO！
Oh, a UFO!
嘘だよ。
Just kidding.
もうさ、シロツメクサ、冠にしてさ。
I'll make a crown out of white clovers.
どこに被ろうかな、これ。
Where should I wear this?
うーん、被れないか。
Hmm, I guess I can't.
じゃあ、はい、あげる！
Then, here, for you!
いやー、お見事お見事。
Wow, well done, well done.
あーもうね、すっかりアイドルかな、これで。
Ah, I guess I'm a full-fledged idol now with this.
あー、100年ぶりぐらいのアイドルっぽいことした！
Ah, I did something idol-like for the first time in about 100 years!
もう、反省会はあとでするけど、
Well, I'll have a review meeting later,
反省会はあとでするけどさ...
I'll have a review meeting later, but...
ちゃんと精進します。
I'll keep working hard.
というわけで、最後に歌ったのは『花に亡霊』と『シルシ』。
And so, the last songs I sang were 'Ghost in a Flower' and 'Shirushi'.
シルシ。
Shirushi.
入り混じらないように、めっちゃカウント作ってもらったのに入り混じ...いや反省会はあとでするんだ。やべやべ。まあ。
Even though they made me a special count so I wouldn't mix them up... wait, I said I'd do the review later. My bad. Anyway.
まだ早かったんかな。でも、でもでもでも、
Maybe it was too soon. But, but but but,
結構、結構結構もうアイドルじゃない？
I'm pretty much an idol now, right?
俺アイドル、めっちゃ良かったって言ってる。やったやったやった！
They're saying 'My idol' was great. Yay, yay, yay!
え、清楚派ですか？清楚？清楚？
Eh, am I the 'seiso' (pure) type? Seiso? Seiso?
清楚な感じする？
Do I feel seiso?
どうですかどうですか？
How is it? How is it?
もう完全に清楚。立ち振る舞い。どうですか？
Totally seiso. My behavior. How is it?
最強のアイドル？え、最強のアイドル？
The strongest idol? Eh, the strongest idol?
嘘、あ、やったー！ありがとう。えー、嬉しい、やったー！
No way, ah, yay! Thank you. I'm so happy, yay!
ポルカはアイドルだよー！イェーイ！嬉しい！ヤッホー！
Polka is an idol! Yay! I'm so happy! Yahoo!
ドキドキドキドキ。いや、いいーね。じゃあ、この感じでじゃあ、この配信どうしていこうかな、この後は。
My heart's racing. This is great. So, with this feeling, how should we proceed with this stream?
あれ？あ、おー！
Wait? Oh, wow!
おまるー！
Omaru!
ポルカー！清楚ー！
Polka! Seiso!
あ、清楚なポルカです。え、え？
Ah, I'm the seiso Polka. Eh, what?
いや、ポルカー！
No, Polka!
はい、ポルカと申します。えっと、5期生、ホロライブ5期生、尾丸ポルカです。よろしくお願いします。
Yes, I'm Polka. Um, 5th generation, Hololive 5th gen, Omaru Polka. Pleased to meet you.
あ、ごめんなさい間違えました。あ、すみません。
Ah, sorry, I made a mistake. My apologies.
あ、すみません、ポルカ、失礼します。すみません、バイバイ、お疲れ様でした。
Excuse me, Polka is leaving. Sorry, bye-bye, thank you for your hard work.
というわけで、来てくださったのは5期生のみなさまでーす！
And so, the ones who came are the members of the 5th generation!
イェーイ！可愛かったでしょー！可愛かったでしょー！
Yay! I was cute, right? Wasn't I cute?!
エモかった。
It was emotional.
あ、エモかったわ。
Ah, it really was emotional.
なんかお前消えるのか？みたいな感じだったけど。
It kind of felt like, 'Wait, are you disappearing?'
消えんわ！
I'm not disappearing!
消えたらどうすんだよ！どうすんだよ！
What would you do if I disappeared?! What would you do?!
エモエモだった。消えんわ！
It was super emotional. I'm not disappearing!
びっくりした！
I was surprised!
ありがとう今日来てくれて。
Thank you for coming today.
いいえー。
You're welcome.
でもさ、どうかな？可愛いだけでポルカ今後生きていけるかな？
But, what do you think? Can Polka survive just by being cute from now on?
うーん、なんかもう、もうひとつ武器が欲しいね。
Hmm... I feel like you need one more weapon.
あー、そうだね。
Ah, you're right.
プロデューサーさん！プロデューサーさん！ポルカ頑張ります！
Producer! Producer! Polka will do her best!
どういうポルカPとしてね、ちょっとね、面白さもちょっと欲しいよね。
As Polka-P, I'd say we want a bit of humor too, you know?
面白さですか？今、あの、作った台本を読んでいただいておりますので…
Humor? Right now, they are reading a script I prepared, so...
いや、言うな言うな！
Hey, don't say that!
おい！ないかやそんな、ないから！
Hey! There's no such thing, there's not!
はい。面白さ、ですか？面白さ。
Yes. Humor, you say? Humor.
台本読んでんの、お前じゃよ！
You're the one reading the script!
えっと、読むな！読むな！台本読むな！読むな！
Um... Don't read it! Don't read the script!
えっと、面白いっていうのは一体どういうことなんですか？
Um, what exactly does "funny" mean?
じゃあ今日はね、そんな尾丸ポルカさんに対して我々、ま、5期生の3人がね、
So today, for Polka-san, us three 5th gen members...
なんかアイテムをひとつずつ使っていって、ちょっと尾丸ポルカさんに面白いことをしてもらおうかなと思ってます。
...will use items one by one and have her do something funny with them.
えー！びっくりびっくり！大物ボケみたいな感じね。
Eh! Surprise, surprise! Like a big physical comedy bit.
モノボケ！
Item improv!
もうちょい新鮮な反応してくれ！
Give a fresher reaction!
嘘っ、モノボケ！？何それ？どうやってやるの？
No way, item improv!? What's that? How do you do it?
どういうこと？でも私が紹介するんだって、これから使用できる、あのね、
What does that mean? But I'm the one introducing the items we can use.
モノボケするんだったら、ポルカこれ使えると思うよ。ちょっと待って、モノボケアイテム持ってくるわ。
If we're doing item improv, I think Polka can use these. Wait a sec, I'll go get the items.
あ、持ってくる？
Oh, she's bringing them?
早く早く持ってきて。
Hurry up and bring them.
これとか？
How about this?
ハンマー！
A hammer!
ピコハン、ピコハン。
Squeaky hammer, squeaky hammer.
どうかな？
How's this?
これね、お肉。ムシャムシャ…
This is meat. Munch munch...
他には？
Any others?
はい、他ですね。
Yes, others.
あのこれ、ししろんのさ…
Um, this is Shishiron's...
あー、手榴弾！
Ah, a hand grenade!
危ないぞ、危ないぞ。
That's dangerous, that's dangerous.
もしかしてまだある？
Is there more by any chance?
こちらです。
It's this one.
これラミィちゃんのおでんじゃない？
Isn't this Lamy-chan's oden?
おでんだ！おでん落ちちゃった！
It's oden! The oden fell!
大人気なんだけど大丈夫かな？
It's very popular, but is it okay?
おでん美味しそう。いいな。
The oden looks delicious. Lucky.
え、まだ？
Eh, there's more?
あーっ！何だよ！
Ah! What the heck?!
光るんですよこれ。
This glows.
次々出てくるじゃん。
They keep coming out.
再利用は大事ですよやっぱり。
Recycling is important, after all.
YAGOO、YAGOO。YAGOO再利用していこう。
YAGOO, YAGOO. Let's recycle YAGOO.
お前自分のとこの社長を再利用って…
Recycling your own CEO...
再利用していこう。
Let's recycle him.
お前より大きくなくていいよ。
He doesn't need to be bigger than you.
ポルカ見せてよ。
Show us Polka.
これがありますけど。
We have this, though.
ラインナップがすげえな。
What a lineup.
奇跡的に並んじゃったんだけど。
They ended up lined up miraculously.
やめてやめて、おい、やめろって。
Stop it, stop it, hey, I said stop.
5期生のメンバーとかじゃないから。
He's not a 5th gen member.
もっとモノボケと言ってもらって…
Do more item improv...
寄せんな、寄せんな。
Don't move him closer, don't move him closer.
5期生になってるじゃん。
He looks like a 5th gen member.
お父さんみたい。
Like a father.
授業参観に来たお父さんみたいになってんじゃねーよ。
Don't look like a father visiting school for a class observation.
やだなちょっと、やめよう。ごめんよけた。
I don't like this, let's stop. Sorry, I moved him away.
で、これを使ってポルカがすごい大爆笑の渦に巻き込むような面白いことをしてくれると。
And with these, Polka will do something funny that draws everyone into a whirlwind of laughter.
はい、何を使いたいか教えてもらって。
Yes, tell us what you want to use.
ポルカ頑張ります！
Polka will do her best!
誰から行く？
Who goes first?
じゃ、ねね行くわ、ねね。
Then, I'll go, Nene.
じゃあ、じゃあお肉を使って…
Then, then use the meat...
くつろぐな！くつろぐな！
Don't relax! Don't relax!
配信中だぞ！
We're streaming!
お肉を使ってねねのことを褒めてください。
Use the meat to praise Nene.
尚且つね、みんなを笑顔にしてね。よろしくね。
And make everyone smile too. Good luck.
面白いんだろうなー、大爆笑だ。
It's going to be funny, a big laugh.
わかりました。
Understood.
じゃあ行きます！はい。もうね、ねねは…
Here I go! Yes. You see, Nene is...
この焼けた肉とは違う。ねねは…
She's different from this cooked meat. Nene is...
ミディアム・レアなんだ。もう美味しさが…
...Medium Rare. Her deliciousness...
これからどんどん焼けて、美味くなっていく。
...is going to be cooked more and more from now on, and get even tastier.
もうこれは、いやダメ。これは…
This is already, no, wait. This is...
何してたの急に？
What were you doing all of a sudden?
これはもう焼けている。つまり、これから食べられるだけ。
This one is already cooked. Meaning it's just ready to be eaten.
でもねねはミディアム・レアだから、これからさらに焼きたい人は焼けばいいし…
But Nene is medium rare, so if people want to cook her more, they should...
ねねが自ら望んで
Nene might even want to...
焼かれてもいい。
...be roasted of her own accord.
炎上？
Online backlash?
そんなことじゃないよ。
That's not what I mean.
炎上...
Backlash...
炎上... 調理されてもいい。調理されてもいい。
Roasting... or being cooked is fine too. Either is fine.
ねねがこれから自分で磨き上げて、美味しくなっていくもいい。
It's fine for Nene to polish herself from now on and become delicious.
なるほど。
I see.
おまる食べてくれんの？じゃあもし焼いたらねねが。
Are you gonna eat me then? If I get roasted, that is.
私はミディアムレアが好きなん。ねね。
I like mine medium-rare, Nene.
おえっ、今食べてもいい？
Whoa, can I eat you now?
今いいよ。食べていい。
You can eat me now. Go ahead.
いんだって！
She said it's okay!
明日、明日ハイパネ口なのにいいの？今食べて。
Tomorrow, even though I have a collab tomorrow, is it okay? To eat me now.
いいよ、食べちゃって。
It's fine, go ahead and eat.
え？え？
Eh? Eh?
食べるのかよ！
You're actually gonna eat me?!
じゃあ、この後ポルカが美味しくいただきました。
Well then, Polka enjoyed her meal afterwards.
はい、というわけで、生焼けのねねでした。
Okay, that was the undercooked Nene.
ミディアムレアのこと生焼けっていうのやめてくれる？ミディアムレアなんだけど！
Can you stop calling medium-rare "undercooked"? It's medium-rare!
はい、ミディアムレアだね。
Right, right. Medium-rare.
怒るよ。
I'm gonna get mad.
なんでそういうこと言うの？
Why would you say something like that?
なんだったらレアとか美味しいじゃん。
I mean, rare can be delicious too.
ねえ、ししろん。
Right, Shishiron?
いやー、なかなかこれは、おまるには厳しかったようなので、ラミィに引き継ぎたいと思います。
Well, this seemed a bit too tough for Polka, so I'd like to hand it over to Lamy.
ラミィお願いしますよ。お願いしますよ。
Lamy, if you please. We're counting on you.
あの、さっき火の輪があったじゃん。あれを使ってボケてください。シンプルな。
You know that ring of fire from earlier? Use that to do a bit. Something simple.
シンプルじゃん、それは。
That sounds simple enough.
フーッ、ハーッ、ハーッ、ハーッ、え？これを使って。
(Breathing heavily) What? Use this?
そうそう、それ。
Yeah, that's the one.
分かった。えーっと。
Got it. Let's see...
ちょっと待って。今、今、降りてきてます。
Wait a sec. It's coming... it's coming to me.
煽る、煽る。
Build it up, build it up.
降りてきてる。降りてきてる。
It's coming... it's coming...
お、いいぜ。
Oh, nice.
ちょ、ねね、いつものさ、デデデくれない？
Hey Nene, can you give me that usual "Da-da-da"?
デデデデデ。
Da-da-da-da-da!
まだ早いです、ねねさん。
That was too early, Nene-san.
今こういう感じになってから「カーン」って言ってくれるんで。
Wait until it feels like this, and then someone say "Ding!"
今いいですか？「カーン」って言った後で。
Can we do it now? Right after the "Ding!"
はい、行きます。
Okay, here we go.
デデデデデ。
Da-da-da-da-da!
通り抜け。
Passing through...
くぐり。
...the hoop!
これを使ってくぐると。
If I go through this...
うわあああああ。
Waaaaaaaah!
ここは。
This place is...
北極？
...the North Pole?
ポルカ北極に来ちゃった。どうしよう。
Polka ended up at the North Pole! What should I do?
え、すごい寒い。無理や。
Whoa, it's freezing! I can't take it.
ああ、もう無理だ。帰ろう。帰ろう帰ろう。
Ah, I'm done. Let's head back. Heading back, heading back.
よいしょ。ああ。
Heave-ho! Ah.
戻ってきたよみんな。ただいま。
I'm back, everyone! I'm home.
ポルカおかえり。
Welcome back, Polka.
おかえりなさい。
Welcome home.
大変です。
This is bad.
コメント欄が北極です。コメント欄が。
The comment section is like the North Pole.
ヒエヒエ。
It's freezing in there.
自ら北極を作り出しちゃったか。
So she ended up creating the North Pole herself.
低温が。ヒエヒエ。
It's freezing. So chilly.
自ら北極を。
Creating the North Pole herself...
逆にそこまで見越したネタだったってことね。
Or maybe the joke was intended to be that bad from the start.
なるほどな。
I see, I see.
それはすごい。
That's pretty impressive.
じゃあラミィだったらどうするんだよ。
Then what would you do if you were Lamy?
まさかに人に振らないで。
Don't just dump it on someone else!
これ使って、次、次、次。
Use this! Next, next, next!
はいはい。
Okay, okay.
どうしました。
What's going on?
じゃあ私で行きましょう。
Okay, let's go with me.
はい。じゃあどうしようかな。
Right. Now, what should I do...
え、もうYAGOOはいいかな？分かりました。
Eh, is YAGOO okay now? Got it.
熱っ！
Hot!
熱いよそこ。
It's hot over there!
じゃあね、はい、グレネード使おう、グレネード。
Well then, let's use the grenade. The grenade!
あ、うん、ししろんの。
Ah, right. Shishiron's.
いつものやつ。
The usual one.
じゃあ私がグレネードをあの、ポイって投げるから。
Okay, I'm gonna toss the grenade, like "poi".
え？はい。
Eh? Okay.
投げられた反応、なんかして。面白い反応してください。
Give me a reaction to getting hit. Something funny.
だから持ってる、それは私が投げたやつが、
So you're holding it... the one I threw went over to Polka.
おまるのところに行ったっていう体。
That's the setup.
面白いっていうかさ、死ぬやん。
Forget "funny", I'm gonna die!
いや大丈夫、死なない死なない。
No, it's fine. You won't die.
ちょっとダメージ受けるだけ。受けるだけ。
You'll just take a little damage. Just a bit.
ヒットポイント30ぐらいだから大丈夫。
It's only about 30 HP, so you'll be fine.
え、お、分かったじゃあ。
Oh, okay then.
いける？ポルカやるよ。
Ready? Here goes, Polka.
じゃあ「カーン」って言ったら「ポイ」って言うね。
Okay, when the bell goes "Ding!", I'll say "Poi!"
受け取るところからだよ、おまる。
Start from the moment you catch it, Polka.
はい、うん。
Got it.
ポイ！
Poi! (Toss!)
うわああ！
Waaaaaaaah!
どーっ！
(Thud!)
無理。もう何、死ぬ。助けて。
No way. I'm... I'm dying. Help!
5期生、5期生助けて。
5th gen... 5th gen, help me!
YAGOO？
YAGOO?
YAGOOなんでよ。
Why YAGOO?!
弊社の社長に頼るな。
Don't rely on our company's CEO!
見えてないしな、こっちから。
I can't even see him from here.
しかもYAGOO埋まっとるし。
And YAGOO is half-buried!
5期生助けて。もうやだ。
5th gen, help! I've had enough.
5期生が、浮かんでる。
The 5th gen... they're floating.
あ、あれがねね、あれがラミィ、あれがししろ。
Ah, that one's Nene, that one's Lamy, and that one's Shishiro.
あら、星になっちゃったわ。
Oh dear, they've all become stars.
5期生の三角星。
The 5th gen triangle stars.
すごい、浮かんでる。すごい、浮かんでる。
Incredible... they're floating. Incredible... they're floating.
はい、カーンカーンカーン。起きて起きて。
Okay, ding-ding-ding! Wake up, wake up!
朝だよ、起きて。
It's morning! Wake up!
お湯、起きて起きて。
Hey you, wake up, wake up!
モノポケ撮影会!?
Mono Poke Photo Shoot!?
大丈夫？今まで記憶ある？大丈夫？
Are you okay? Do you remember everything until now? Are you okay?
えっと…なんか…
Uh... well...
えっとデビューして…
Uh, I debuted...
みんなでデビューしたじゃん。
We all debuted together, right?
そっから？そこから？今日の、今日の記憶でいいんだよ。
From then? From that point? Just today's, today's memories are fine.
今日か。今日は…えっと…
Today. Today is... uh...
あ！もしかして、今配信中ですか？
Ah! By any chance, are we live right now?
そうなんだよ実は。実はそうなんだよ、おまる。
Actually, we are. That's how it is, Omaru.
という事はおまるは、ボケをしなければいけない時間なんだ。
Which means it's time for Omaru to be the funny one.
ボ、ボケ！？
F-funny one!?
そう。
Yes.
ど、どうやって？
H-how?
さあおまる、そのYAGOOを使って…
Now, Omaru, use that YAGOO...
YAGOO？
YAGOO?
YAGOOが座員だった時、どんな感じの反応をするか、面白くやってみてごらん。
Show us in a funny way how you'd react if YAGOO was a trainee.
YAGOO！？
YAGOO!?
YAGOOが座員だった時…ちょっと待って、いないけど！
If YAGOO was a trainee... wait, he's not even here!
そんな、YAGOOが座員だったらなんて、出来るのか！？
Doing something like YAGOO being a trainee, is that even possible!?
やるんだよ！
You have to do it!
コメント欄…えっと、古参座員、オラに力をくれ！
Comment section... uh, veteran trainees, lend me your strength!
いくぞお前ら！みんなでかかるぞ！
Let's go, guys! Everyone, let's do this!
行きます、それではショートコント：もしYAGOOが新人座員だったら。
Here I go. Now for a short skit: What if YAGOO was a rookie trainee.
あ、メンバーシップありがとうございます！おまる座にようこそ！あ…
Ah, thank you for the membership! Welcome to Omaru-za! Ah...
あ、YAGOOさんですか？あ、ありがとうございます。え…
Ah, is it YAGOO-san? Ah, thank you. Eh...
え、でも知ってますよこの人。うちスタンプでこれYAGOOいるんです、そもそも。あ…
Wait, I know this person. We have a stamp of him, to begin with. Ah...
え、すごいですね。YAGOO…あ…え？
Wow, that's amazing. YAGOO... ah... eh?
YAGOOうちの座員になったん？え？
YAGOO became our trainee? Eh?
ど、どう…明日像の…像磨くけど、一緒にやる？
H-how... tomorrow I'm polishing the elephant, want to join?
うわ！磨い…あ！お前の光がすげーすげーすげー！
Whoa! Polish... ah! Your glow is amazing, amazing, amazing!
じゃあ、YAGOOは照明係です。あの、これからうちの…
Then, YAGOO is the lighting technician. From now on...
ありがとうございます、点灯照明光らせてくれるそうです。彼も喜んでおります。
Thank you, he says he'll light up the place. He's happy too.
やった！一緒にこれから頑張ろうね、座員として。うん！
Yay! Let's work hard together from now on as trainees. Yeah!
頑張るよ！よしありがとう。YAGOOチャンネル登録よろしくお願いします！
I'll do my best! Okay, thank you. Subscribe to YAGOO channel!
穴空いちゃいましたね、ちょっと。
I've left a bit of a void there, haven't I?
ちょっと…ちょっとお疲れなのかもしれない。
Maybe... maybe you're a little tired.
おでこ撃ち抜かれてたら…疲れておでこが撃ち抜かれる事があるかーい！
Getting shot through the forehead... how could being tired result in getting shot through the forehead!?
よし、もう次行こう、次。
Okay, let's go to the next one, next.
次次、次行こう。甘いなネタ、たんたん…
Next, next! Let's go. A sweet skit...
おでんおでんおでん…はいはいはい！
Oden oden oden... yes yes yes!
せっかくだからおでん使おう。うん。
Since we're at it, let's use the oden. Yeah.
すぐね、すぐ落ちちゃうんですよこの…はいはいはい。
It falls off easily, this... yes yes yes.
はい、じゃあこのおでん…はい、おまる持った。
Okay, then this oden... okay, Omaru has it.
それラミィの特製手作りおでん！
That's Lamy's special handmade oden!
ボケて。
Do a boke.
ただいま。え？これ？ポルカに？
I'm home. Eh? This? For Polka?
ラミィおでん作ってくれたの？
Lamy, you made oden for me?
ラミィおでん…
Lamy, you made oden...
ラミィおでん作ってくれたの？
Lamy, you made oden for me?
おまる、ワンパターンになってる、おまるヤバい。
Omaru, you're repeating yourself! This is bad!
違う違う違う、ラミィが、ラミィが、こう…くれた…
No, no, no! Lamy, Lamy... gave it to me like this...
そうだよ、そうだよ。
Yes, I did.
そうなんだ！え、どこら辺こだわったの？え、ポルカこの…
Wow! What parts were you picky about? Eh, Polka this...
うわ、急にラミィに振ってくスタイルだね。
Whoa, suddenly passing the buck to Lamy, huh.
こんにゃくが好きだな。
I like the konnyaku.
はいよ、食べな食べな。
Alright, eat up, eat up.
分かった。もぐもぐもぐ…
Understood. *munch munch munch*...
ラミィのためならば皿まで食ってやる。よしよしよし！よし！
For Lamy's sake, I'll even eat the plate. All right, all right! All right!
ほら！うまい、うまい！
Look! It's delicious, delicious!
ラミィのおでん！うおー！
Lamy's oden! Uwoo!
ラミィのおでん旨すぎる！販売してくれ！
Lamy's oden is too good! Please sell it!
味の感想になってるじゃんもう。ただ食べただけの人だよそれ。
You're just giving food reviews now. That's just someone who ate it.
じゃあもう最後、最後、最後やろ。
Then let's do the last one, last, last.
おまる、まだ大丈夫、まだ大丈夫。まだへらってません。大丈夫。
Omaru, you're still okay. You haven't snapped yet. You're okay.
まだへらってない。次でやめない？
Not snapped yet. Should we stop after the next one?
あったまってきたあったまってきた。
I'm warming up, I'm warming up.
はい、おまるじゃあ、ピコピコハンマーあるじゃん。
Okay, Omaru, you have a squeaky hammer, right?
あった！持って…オーケー、任せて！持ってるよ。
I found it! Holding... okay, leave it to me! I'm holding it.
じゃあここでひとつ。ピコハンとかけまして、ししろんと解く。
Then, let's do one here. A riddle: Picohan and Shishiron.
はい！
Yes!
一番ムズ！難しい。
That's the hardest! Difficult.
その心は？
And the answer?
ピコハンとかけまして、ししろんと解く。その心は…
Picohan and Shishiron. The answer is...
どちらも…戦闘力が…100万！
Both have a combat power of... ONE MILLION!
一滑りプレゼントします！
Here's a joke that fell flat for you!
モノボケ撮影会！？
Prop Comedy Photoshoot!?
1滑りポイント、ありがとうございます。
One 'failed joke' point, thank you very much.
100滑りポイントで何か景品と交換できるようにしといて。
Make it so you can exchange 100 failed joke points for a prize.
100滑り！？
100 failed jokes!?
五期生... 頑張ります...
5th Gen... I'll do my best...
頑張れ。
Good luck.
ということで、このモノボケは五期生の提供でお送りいたしました。
And so, this prop comedy segment was brought to you by the 5th Gen.
え、嘘でしょ？
Eh, you're kidding, right?
でも今までで一番よかったじゃない？
But wasn't that the best one yet?
あ、でもね、頑張った。頑張った！
Ah, but you know, you worked hard. You did your best!
そうなんだよね、頑張った。ありがとうございます。
That's right, I did my best. Thank you very much.
ぜひまた、うちの配信に遊びに来てください。
Please come visit my stream again sometime.
はい！びあー！
Yes! See ya!
行くよ。見てね。
We're going now. Watch us.
え、嬉しい、なんか、五期生好き。
Eh, I'm happy somehow, eh, I love the 5th Gen.
もう疲れ果てて語彙力なくなっちゃったじゃない。
You're so exhausted you've lost your vocabulary.
集中して。
Concentrate.
誕生日に集中してくれ。
Focus on your birthday.
お前が主役だよ、今日は。
You're the main character today.
そう、頑張ってね。楽しんでね。
Right, do your best. Have fun.
あ、誕生日おめでとうってもう一回言って。
Oh, say "happy birthday" one more time.
誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
やったー！いつも雑な振りに返してくれてありがとう！ありがとう！
Yay! Thank you for always responding to my random prompts! Thank you!
頑張れ！頑張ってね！
Do your best! Hang in there!
バイバイ。頑張ってね。可愛いな。バイバイ。行かないで。
Bye-bye. Do your best. So cute. Bye-bye. Don't go.
行かないで... あ、帰ってきた。あ、いいよ大丈夫だよ。ありがとう。
Don't go... oh, they came back. Oh, it's fine, it's okay. Thank you.
本当に行かないで、帰ることになっちゃう。
Really, don't go, I'll have to end this and go home.
遊びすぎてしまった、もしやポルカこれ。
Did I play around too much, perhaps?
え、どうなんだろう。ちょ... あれ？あれ？もう？え？
Eh, I wonder. Wai... huh? Huh? Already? Eh?
え、く、え、時間、あ、あ、じゃあ、あの、あ、あの、えと、あの...
Eh, ku, eh, time, ah, ah, then, um, ah, um, er, um...
何か、ある、ある、あるのかな。何か、あの、もう、えと...
Is there, is there, is there something? Something, um, already, er...
はい。
Yes.
あの... はい。
Um... yes.
え？あ、ぐ、あ、は、はい。はい、はい、あ。
Eh? Ah, gu, ah, ha, yes. Yes, yes, ah.
すみません、あの、もう全部、今、頭の中空っぽになっちゃった。
Sorry, um, my mind has gone completely blank now.
はい、というわけで、えと、なんと、今日、告知がございます。
Yes, and so, er, surprisingly, I have an announcement today.
や、すみません、なんか途中で、エモいのあれを切らしてしまいましたので、ちょっともう頭が混乱して参りましたが。
I'm sorry, I kind of ran out of that "emotional energy" halfway through, so my head is a bit confused, but...
告知をさせてください！どうぞ！
Please let me make an announcement! Here you go!
尾丸ポルカ 誕生日記念 2021
Omaru Polka Birthday Celebration 2021
こちら！尾丸ポルカ 誕生日記念 2021！
This! Omaru Polka Birthday Celebration 2021!
はい、えと、ちょっと時間だいぶ私、あの、やってしまって、もう販売しちゃっているのかもしれないです。
Yes, er, with the timing, I might have messed up and they might be on sale already.
申し訳ないです。えとこちら、えと、ボイス＆グッズ全部セット、記念ボイス全部セット、記念グッズ三種セット。
I'm very sorry. Um, here we have the Voice & Goods Full Set, Commemorative Voice Full Set, and the 3-item Commemorative Goods Set.
こちら、お母さんのこうましろ先生が描いてくれた、えと、イラストとともに...
These come with the illustration that my "mother," Koumashiro-sensei, drew for me...
あのこれポルカが無理言ったんだけど、アクリルパネルに箔押しのメッセージが入ってます。
Um, I specifically asked for this, but the acrylic panel has a gold-stamped message on it.
そして寺田てら先生によるアクリルキーホルダー＆ステッカー描き下ろし、こちらもイラストが描かれているんですけども。
And also an acrylic key holder and sticker by Terada Tera-sensei, these also feature new illustrations.
これはイラストを使わせてもらった「おまる座」モチーフ サーカスペナント。
And this is the "Omaruza" motif circus pennant using that illustration.
そして、はい、各グッズの画像があります。はい、よろしくお願いします。
And, yes, we have images for each item. Yes, please check them out.
グッズ＆ボイス 全部セット特典
Goods & Voice Full Set Bonus
痛い、痛い、痛い。はいはいはい。え、こちらが、はい、イラスト...
Ow, ow, ow. Yes, yes, yes. Eh, this is the illustration...
になってる。こちらね、あの、全部買うと特典でついてくるイラストポストカード... ちなみに、さっきの絵と違うんやで、こちらは。
This is the illustration postcard that comes as a bonus if you buy the whole set... by the way, this one is different from the previous picture.
そして特典ボイスがついてきます。よろしくお願いします。
And it comes with a bonus voice. Please look forward to it.
ほら見て違う。あ、そして、なんか箔押しのメッセージがちょっと見えますね。
Look, see, it's different. Ah, and you can see a bit of the gold-stamped message.
これはどうなってるのかな？うん？
I wonder how this one looks? Hmm?
いや、その時のポルカ、めっちゃなんか可愛いな。
Wow, I look really cute in that picture.
え、どう？あ、いい感じですか？
Eh, how is it? Oh, looking good?
あ、ちょっとちょっとちょっと、やめてやめてやめて。いいいいいい、大丈夫、大丈夫。アップにしなくて平気だから。
Ah, wait, wait, wait, stop, stop, stop. It's fine, it's fine, it's okay. You don't need to zoom in.
はい、次の、次の画像どう？
Yes, how about the next, next image?
「おまる座」モチーフ サーカスペナント
"Omaruza" Motif Circus Pennant
こちら、これね、絶対出したかったの、ペナント！
This, I definitely wanted to release this, the pennant!
これ、ふさふさがついてくる。ふさふさがイメージだけど。
This comes with tassels. At least in the image.
わからない、これからふさふさなくなっちゃったらどうしよう。ふさふさがついてる下に。
I don't know, what if the tassels disappear later? There are tassels at the bottom.
この... 五角形？って言うのかな？
This... pentagon? Is that what it's called?
これを付けてもらえました。ありがとうございます。可愛いでしょ。
I was able to have this made. Thank you very much. It's cute, isn't it?
ポルカおるよ。
Polka is there.
寺田てら先生のイラスト、好きなんだ。
I love Terada Tera-sensei's illustrations.
で、こちら大きさ的には、えと...
And size-wise, um...
21センチかけ、あ、21センチ、210ミリだね。
21cm by... ah, 21cm, 210mm.
で、高さが300ミリってことは、30センチです。
And the height is 300mm, which means 30cm.
あ、こっちか。
Ah, this way.
可愛いな。
So cute.
まあ、でもこれだけじゃなくて、ドドン！
Well, but that's not all, ta-dah!
寺田てら先生描き下ろし アクリルキーホルダー＆ステッカー
Acrylic Key Holder & Sticker drawn by Terada Tera-sensei
はい、アクリル...
Yes, acrylic...
アクリルキーホルダーそしてステッカー
The acrylic key holder and sticker
寺田てら先生描き下ろし
アクリルキーホルダー＆ステッカー
Newly drawn by Terada Tera-sensei
Acrylic Key Holder & Sticker
貼れる、ついに
can finally be stuck on things.
貼れる
You can stick them.
いいでしょ、いいでしょ
Nice, right? Nice, right?
これさ、玉乗ってんだよ。
Look, I'm riding a ball.
さっきのとは全身なかったんだけど、これちゃんと玉乗ってるようになってるから。
The previous ones weren't full body, but these are showing me riding a ball properly.
こちらも、よろしくお願いいたします！
Please check these out too!
で、えーっと
And, um...
まあ、記念ボイスもめっちゃ頑張って撮ったよ。
Well, I also worked really hard on the anniversary voice pack.
よろしくお願いします。
Please check it out.
ちょっとね、結構、あの、あんまりよそではないシチュエーションボイスを撮ったよ。
I recorded a situation voice that's quite rare elsewhere.
あの、ぜひ気になる人は、もうたぶんブースが出ちゃっているんで、よろしくお願いします。
If you're interested, the Booth link is probably already live, so please check it out.
よろしくお願いします。はい。
Please check it out. Yes.
では…
Now...
まあ五期生と一緒に、本当は歌いたかったなー。
Actually, I really wanted to sing with my 5th-gen mates.
なんか寂しくなっちゃったな。
I'm starting to feel a bit lonely.
やっぱ戻ってきてもらう。今から通話とかかけられますかね？
I want them back. Can I give them a call now?
あの…無理かな？
Um... is it impossible?
コラボしたいな。
I want to collab.
ちょっと待って分かった。
Wait, I've got it.
錬成すればいい、今ここで。
I'll just transmute them, right here, right now.
行くぞ。
Here goes.
はっ！えいっ！五期生出でよ！
Ha! Ei! 5th gen, come forth!
ふんっ！だーっ！
Hun! Da!
あれ？
Huh?
はっ！とーっ！
Ha! Toh!
あーっ！
Aah!
あれ？失敗し…
Huh? I failed...
うわあ！なんだなんだ？降ってきたなんかが。
Whoa! What's this? Something's falling.
なんか降ってきたけど、座員じゃなくて今五期生が欲しいんだって。
Something fell, but I don't want Zain right now, I want the 5th gen!
うおー違う違う違う！五期生が欲しい！あーっ！
Whoa, no, no, no! I want the 5th gen! Aah!
五期生どこ？
Where is the 5th gen?
うちの同期ー！
My generation mates!
どこ？
Where?
と、どこなの？
Wh- Where are you?
何も見えない。
I can't see anything.
え？
Eh?
はっ？
Ha?
どういうことだこれは？
What's going on?
おおーっ！やった！
Ooh! I did it!
やった五期生、来てくれた！
Yes, 5th gen, you're here!
けど、なんか、みんなペラペラになっちゃってね。
But, uh, you've all become so thin.
まあいいか。こうなったら一人で四人分盛り上げるぞ！
Well, whatever. I'll hype things up as much as the four of us combined!
行くぜお前ら、最後の盛り上がりを見せてくれ！
Let's go, everyone! Show me one last burst of energy!
歌います。
I'll sing.
ふんっ！はーっ！
Hun! Hah!
ここ！
Here!
行くぞー！
Here we go!
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to, welcome to Japari Park!
ようこそジャパリパークへ
Welcome to Japari Park
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Another day of hullabaloo and chaos
作詞・作曲 / 大石昌良
Lyrics and Composition / Masayoshi Oishi
うおー、お祭り！ありがとうございます！
Whoa, it's a festival! Thank you so much!
超楽しかった！
That was so much fun!
行くぞ！
Let's go!
高らかに笑い合えばフレンズ
If we laugh out loud together, we're friends
はい！
Hai!
喧嘩して すっちゃかめっちゃかしても仲良し
Even if we fight and things get messy, we're still close
うっ、はっ、ふー！
Ugh, ha, fuu!
けものはいても のけものはいない
There are animals, but no one's an outcast
本当の愛はここにある
True love is found right here
ほら、君も手をつないで大冒険
Look, you too, let's hold hands and go on a grand adventure
One, two, three
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to, welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Another day of hullabaloo and chaos
姿かたちも十人十色だから惹かれあうの
With all our different shapes and sizes, that's why we're drawn to each other
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら
When we gently touch our fingers against the sunset sky
はじめまして
Pleased to meet you
君をもっと知りたいな
I want to know you better
お、すごい！一緒に踊ってる！
Oh, amazing! We're dancing together!
うおー！
Whoa!
振り向けば あちらこちらでトラブル
If you turn around, there's trouble here and there
えい、はー！
Ei, hah!
待って、こたえて、あわてん坊は どーまんなか
Wait, answer me, the scatterbrain is right in the center
けものですもの 大目に見ててね
Since we're animals, please be patient with us
みんな自由に生きている
Everyone's living freely
そう、君も飾らなくて大丈夫
That's right, you don't need to put on an act either
One, two, three Nice to meet you ようこそジャパリパーク！
One, two, three Nice to meet you, welcome to Japari Park!
今日からどうぞよろしくね
From today on, nice to meet you
いつもいつでも 優しい笑顔 君を待っていたの
I was always waiting for you with a gentle smile
開かれたゲート 夢をいっぱい語ったら
Through the opened gate, if we talk about all our dreams
どこまでも続いてゆくグレートジャーニー
This Great Journey will continue forever
ここは、ここは！
This place, this place is!
え、ほらほら！ホロライブのみんな見てますか？
Eh, look, look! Is everyone in Hololive watching?
こんなに、五期生と一緒にステージ立てたよ！
Look at this, I got to stand on stage with the 5th gen!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
行くぞー！
Here we go!
おおー！
Ooh!
東へ吠えろ 西へ吠えろ
Howl to the east, howl to the west
世界中に響けサファリメロディ
Let the Safari Melody echo across the world
ようこそジャパリパークへ
Welcome to Japari Park!
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク
Welcome to, welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today is a wild commotion too!
姿かたちも十人十色
Shapes and sizes are all different,
だから惹かれ合うの
that's why we're drawn to each other.
夕暮れ空に
If I gently place my fingers
指をそっと添えたら
against the sunset sky...
はじめまして
Nice to meet you,
君をもっと知りたいな
I want to know you more!
いくぞ！最後一緒に！
Let's go! One last time together!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la, la la la la,
Oh Welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
Oh, Welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la, la la la la,
集まれ友達
Gather around, friends!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la, la la la la,
Oh Welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
Oh, Welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la, la la la la,
素敵な旅立ち
A wonderful departure!
ようこそジャパリパークへ
Welcome to Japari Park!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
この後のプレミア公開、見てください！
Please watch the premiere after this!
よろしく！
Don't miss it!
またねー！
See you later!
あ、ねね、明日頑張れ！
Ah, Nene, do your best tomorrow!
3D LIVE #尾丸ポルカ爆誕祭 告知アリ
3D LIVE #OmaruPolkaBirthdayCelebration - Notification Included